THE ELUSIVE
SAMURAI
The true way to use a real sword
is not by stabbing forcefully.
It's much like using
a kitchen knife or a saw.
The blade cuts the best when it is pulled.
To cut as you retreat.
Don't you think it's the best technique
for an elusive person like you?
But I couldn't take a life
with this method.
At most, I could cut hide or meat.
That's okay.
That's precisely what makes it
the Elusive Sword.
Your raised left hand
will serve as a guide.
Wait for the moment when your enemy's
blade passes between your hand and sword.
Here he comes!
Twist my upper body counterclockwise.
Let the weight of the sword
do the work as I lower it.
Pull the blade to the right
and retreat!
My inner forearm.
I don't have any armor here
because it's a difficult spot to aim for,
and it impedes my movement.
You know the weak points
of an armored warrior well.
But it's not a terrible weakness.
It'll take quite some time for me to lose
consciousness with just a bleeding wrist.
You think I won't kill you
before that happens?
In this small room!
I'll corner you slow and steady.
I can just take my time to tend
to my wound after I cut you into pieces.
Why did I shiver just now?
He's a naginata expert.
He won't let me get a single blow in!
You're light, small,
and lack experience!
You two will die here.
What a shame.
In ten years, you probably would have
become a skilled master.
If that were the case,
you could have known many pleasures.
The sophisticated pleasure of using your
body and strength to kick about the weak,
the pleasure of stealing,
the pleasure of taking a woman…
That's what my boss taught me
when he took me under his wing.
Something your virtuous leader
Yorishige Suwa can't do.
Lord Yorishige isn't…
Huh?
…our lord now.
Is that so?
Regardless of who you serve,
it's all the same.
Your lord is clueless.
They couldn't even teach you brats
about any fulfilling pleasures
and left you to die
for this worthless village.
So you shut up.
Am I spot-on?
Yeah, it's true.
Our lord is soft, naive,
and tends to run away.
But compared to you who has grown fat
by sacrificing the weak, my Big Brother,
who commands us to protect the weak,
has much more integrity as a warrior.
You're still here?
Resisting with a brat's toy
like the trash you are!
Persistent brat.
There's no way a mere child can penetrate
the defense of a grown man's naginata.
Stop calling me
a brat!
I can't be so carefree
to be thinking about the far future.
We have a year and a half
until Lord Yorishige's prophecy.
We won't be useful
in the Young Lord's great war
if we can't beat adults while we're ten.
What…
I can't believe I'm being defeated
by some nameless brats.
Go be with the demons in hell.
Our lord is Tokiyuki Hojo.
What?
Kamakura's…
rightful heir!
There's no way!
I can't hit him!
This is bad.
I have to stop the bleeding.
He's not only evading my sword,
but also my splattering blood?
Is he a monster?
A transforming swordsmanship!
It's rare to see one wield a blade
with such precision.
There must be someone
who taught you those techniques.
Who is your teacher?
I don't have to tell you.
A skilled hawk hides everything.
If you show your strength
within an organization,
you'll be taken advantage of
like the small fry and the core members.
Act like a clown and pander to the leader,
and you can be sure to enjoy
just the benefits.
BUDDHA
There is just one brief moment
when I have to use my sharpened talons.
The moment when I kill anyone
that recognizes them.
Or when I kill our boss
and take over this party.
To hide yourself is an art of survival
in times of chaos!
Now die and shut up!
To hide… huh.
Die!
There's an ordinary blade
that comes straight,
and a unique blade
in which one bends their wrist.
If you hide it well, your opponent won't
know which is coming until it's too late.
But with him, the height of his elbow is
slightly different
from the moment he pulls back his blade.
Which means he's not
sufficiently hiding his technique.
W-What?
That would be a formidable sword skill
if you could hide it completely,
but you don't understand how it works.
You're not hiding anything special
as I thought.
I'm disappointed.
He wields two swords
and is skilled in martial arts, too.
What else is this kid hiding?
Occupying this village and
the children's tactics are both valuable.
When I find a hidden treasure,
my forlorn body
is slightly brought back to life.
I'm drawn to him for some reason.
Because he's hiding something magnificent.
All right. That's enough from you.
Now.
How is it going, Chojumaru?
This is hopeless.
I'm going to die.
I'll lose too much blood
before I kill this kid.
It's useless. I'm fading.
My life ends here?
Father!
What do you mean
there's no territory for me to inherit?
I'm sorry.
The family has distributed the land
amongst the sons
over generations until
only this small plot remains.
From now on, like all the other families,
we'll give all our territory
to the eldest son.
You live here and help out
your older brother.
You're telling me
to become my brother's servant!
I've been studying martial arts
and the art of war
so that I can protect my own territory!
A warrior without a territory
is not a warrior at all.
If I wanted a place of my own,
I had no choice but to steal it.
It was hell from then on.
Somewhere along the way,
it became pleasurable to take from others.
I sold children.
I felt better about myself by sending them
to futures as dark as my own.
Though I was pursued,
I had nowhere to rest.
I thought I could reverse my fate
when I was recruited into a large battle.
But I was unable to
make a name for myself,
for I was on the losing side.
Your life is always hell, isn't it?
You should flee somewhere
where no one can chase you.
There must be a place
where the light shines.
Don't lie, Kusunoki.
There's no light anywhere.
What's this?
Something shines before me.
I can't win.
Someone who can laugh so purely
in this hellhole cannot be human.
He's even smiling upon someone like me?
My Buddha…
What started as a blade
of compassion had become
hell on earth
by the time the fight was over.
Is it a demon or a buddha that grants
the scoundrel of times of chaos
the death penalty?
Demon-heart Buddha Blade.
You're amazing, Young Lord.
The two of us barely stood a chance
against that monster.
It's all thanks
to the technique Fubuki taught me.
You're right.
Who would have thought
that it would be possible to defeat him
by simply cutting his inner forearm
and running from him?
The Cowardly Sword is impressive!
Don't call it that!
The enemies that remain should run away
when we spread the word
that their general is dead.
We're almost done…
Are you serious?
Sadamune's here!
You again, brat?
"You again"? That's our line!
You're the one invading others' territory!
Shut up! These are the times we live in!
Your eye… I want to feed it to a snake
and watch it swallow it whole.
-What's wrong with you?
Big-Eyed Monster, you're so persistent.
Don't call me a monster!
You basically are a monster
with those eyes!
What did you say about my godly eyes?
Leave it to Sadamune Ogasawara
to bring his reinforcements at this timing
from the village's front entrance.
He's got a keen perception of this war.
Our other allies are busy handling
the enemies that are already here.
We can't win like this.
SOUTH
There are no enemies
on the south end of this village.
We can gather our allies
and all escape from there…
What?
Enemy forces from the south, too?
Nope.
Here we go!
That fire!
Yes, they're reinforcements
from Suwa Grand Shrine.
They made it just in time.
Drat!
Retreat!
Only gather Shokan's soldiers
that are fighting nearby.
B-But, Sadamune…
We lack the preparation
to fight against Suwa's main army.
The war is happening outside, but there's
blood on the inside of the door?
Lord Yorishige, Sadamune
and his presumed army are evacuating!
Chase them away to the border.
Tokitsugu, clean up the bandits
around the village.
YORISHIGE'S SON
TOKITSUGU SUWA
Okay.
-They're getting away.
-Hi.
Genba!
You better be grateful.
We made it in time
because I rode the horse at full speed.
Well, when I saw
a curvy woman on the road,
I was shocked because
my nose started bleeding profusely.
I thought I was a goner.
Don't die!
-What about over there?
-There's no one.
-The enemy's over there.
-Right.
None here. Find them!
Mr. Yorishige.
I'm glad you're safe.
Yes.
That kinda hurts, Mr. Yorishige.
Sadamune. Shokan is…
He's got dumb luck.
He would've croaked if we stopped
the bleeding just a little bit later.
Why did you come for me?
We received word that you and your men
were wasting time committing a massacre.
Suwa's response isn't so stupid as
to let such an opportunity go unnoticed.
Who said to kill the villagers?
You don't get any taxes
from an uninhabited territory.
You idiot.
Punish me as you wish.
However, your strategic insight
this time was incredible.
I will give you a small territory,
so sharpen your fangs there.
Prepare for the decisive battle
against Suwa that will eventually come.
From this day forward,
you are prohibited from being a bandit.
Serve me only as a soldier.
Certainly.
I can tell his will to be a bandit
is gone from his eyes.
Did malice leave his body
along with the blood?
From then on,
rogues gradually fell under the control
of the increasingly powerful governing
feudal lords and eventually disappeared.
This era was the final stage
where the uninhibited
bandit samurai thrived.
There.
There we go.
Mr. Yorishige.
It's all thanks to Fubuki
that the village and I survived.
Please pay him a special sum
from Suwa Grand Shrine.
Oh, is that so?
Of course, we will pay him handsomely!
And one more thing.
I want Fubuki to join my party
as a retainer.
Splendid idea!
Wait, Chojumaru.
I want to be your friend, but becoming
a retainer is a different story.
I want to serve a lord
that can lead the country.
I would consider it
if I were to serve your Lord Suwa…
This one
is the lord.
This one.
My name is Tokiyuki Hojo.
I'm the orphan of the regent
to the Kamakura shogunate, Takatoki Hojo.
I am more or less on an endeavor
to lead the country.
What?
Sorry I hid it from you.
I had decided
to not share my true identity
until I had talked to Mr. Yorishige.
I thought he was hiding
something huge, but…
This secret is too big!
As a commoner,
he's just a kind, elusive boy.
But when you add the fact
that he is a Hojo child…
All of his skills
become formidable weapons!
This is invigorating.
My millet fee will be expensive.
If that's okay, then I will serve you.
I will draw out
all the strength this prince possesses
and join his attempt to win the country.
At Suwa Grand Shrine, we're allowed to
eat rice instead of millet.
For real? It must be paradise?
I can't tell
if this guy is smart or clueless.
TO BE CONTINUED